Abraham: What is the advantage of
working in a team to working alone?
Working with others in a team
is often better than working
alone for solving problems.
It can increase creativity and allows
for brainstorming ideas and discussing
and sharing solutions to difficult tasks.
Nicole: By working together, teams can
find solutions to problems that work best
by discussing the issues from different
perspectives and different points of view.
Productivity can therefore improve
as more ideas can be developed
and collaboration can increase.
Teams can also compensate for any weakness
in each other’s ideas or theories by
offering a range of solutions which can
be thoroughly discussed and reviewed.
Abraham: Conversely working alone an
increase a person’s independence and help
an individual to make their own decisions.
It can increase an individual’s
self-motivation, initiative and
resourcefulness and help develop
their problem-solving skills.
There are less distractions like team
meetings and the reliance on others
and not everyone feels comfortable
working in a team preferring to work
with minimal direction and supervision.
Nicole: But working alone can be
limiting, no one to bounce ideas off or
offer advice at times of indecision and
teamwork can be beneficial for everyone
even those who prefer to work solo.
When individuals get together with
other independent thinkers to share
ideas and by approaching ideas from
different perspectives, they can bring a
broader range of solutions to a problem.
Abraham: So, let's look at how
team members can work together to
make use of individual strengths.
A strong team should have a good team
ethic which in turn makes it successful.
Successful teams have members with a range
of individual strengths and qualities.
These include good communication,
focus on the task in hand, contributing
to the workload evenly, diverse
members and good leadership.
Nicole: However, this is not to say all
members need all the same qualities and
strengths for a team to be successful.
Team members bring different
attributes to the team.
But remember a team is only as good
as it's component parts and if one of
those parts is not functioning correctly
then the whole team will suffer.
Abraham: Strong and responsible
leadership is one of the key aspects
of maintaining a successful team.
A good leader should be
respected and trusted.
They are the glue that
holds the team together.
Nicole: The person at the top should
be fully aware of everyone’s strengths
and to some extent weaknesses and
what they can bring to the team.
They should be responsible
for setting the pace and offer
encouragement and motivation.
They also need to be aware if
anyone is not performing at their
best, the reason why this is so.
It maybe that they need more support,
or that too much responsibility
has been put on one person.
Abraham: Everyone will be
responsible for their own aspect
and organising their own workload.
Without organisation a
workplace can become chaotic
and the same applies to a team.
Regular meetings can help to make sure
a team is on track and that all members
are working towards the common goal.
Nicole: Everyone is unique and
this is the same in a team.
The members can all offer their own
experiences and knowledge, and everyone
should be assigned activities that are
based on their strengths and skills.
A diverse range of team members can
also bring an extra dimension to a team.